<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='facts.xsl'?>
<facts>
  <fact>
    <numberOfLikes>2</numberOfLikes>
    <text>
      Brad Pitt, who was a big fan of Lock, Stock and Two Smoking Barrels (1998), approached director Guy Ritchie and asked for a role in this film. Ritchie found Pitt couldn't master a London accent, he gave him the role of Mickey the Gypsy.
    </text>
  </fact>
  <fact>
    <numberOfLikes>4</numberOfLikes>
    <text>When Vinny and Sol are sitting outside Brick-Top's Bookies, about to give him the diamond, the man that approaches the car is not really Bullet-Tooth Tony, it was a look-alike. Vinnie Jones didn't show up for shooting that day because he was in jail for fighting the night before.</text>
  </fact>
  <fact>
    <numberOfLikes>6</numberOfLikes>
    <text>
      Franky Four-Fingers changes into four different outfits during the short telephone conversation to cousin Avi.
    </text>
  </fact>
  <fact>
    <numberOfLikes>8</numberOfLikes>
    <text>
      Nearly every death in the movie takes place off-screen.
    </text>
  </fact>
  <fact>
    <numberOfLikes>45</numberOfLikes>
    <text>
      The producers couldn't afford enough extras for the boxing match sequences. Whenever a camera angle changed, the extras had to move around to create an impression of a crowded house.
    </text>
  </fact>
  <fact>
    <numberOfLikes>23</numberOfLikes>
    <text>
      In the final scene, the 86-carat diamond is referred to as an 84-carat diamond.
    </text>
  </fact>
  <fact>
    <numberOfLikes>15</numberOfLikes>
    <text>
      According to the DVD commentary, Bow, the dog was very difficult to work with. During car scene with Vincent, Sol and Tyrone, the dog was actually attacking Lennie James, and James was actually bitten in the crotch by the dog but didn't suffer any serious injury. The dog was replaced after that incident.
    </text>
  </fact>
  <fact>
    <numberOfLikes>345</numberOfLikes>
    <text>
      To keep things in order during production, director Guy Ritchie introduced a system of fines on set. There were fines for mobile phones ringing, arriving late, taking naps during shooting, being "cheeky", being unfunny, and/or moaning and complaining. One staff member was even charged for letting the craft service table run out of coffee cups.
    </text>
  </fact>
  <fact>
    <numberOfLikes>23</numberOfLikes>
    <text>
      Guy Ritchie reportedly paid US $1 million for the use of Madonna's song, "Lucky Star".
    </text>
  </fact>
  <fact>
    <numberOfLikes>976</numberOfLikes>
    <text>
      When Mickey "wins" a new trailer van for his mother from Turkish, he specifically picks out "periwinkle blue" as the color. In Psycho (1960), we are told that Norman Bates helped to pick out a "periwinkle blue" dress for his dead mother. Mickey, just like Norman, is also responsible (albeit indirectly) for his own mother's death.
    </text>
  </fact>
  <fact>
    <numberOfLikes>213</numberOfLikes>
    <text>
      Vinnie Jones' character goes after a dog with a knife to cut him open after swallowing a diamond. In "Gone in Sixty Seconds" his character is stopped from cutting open a dog who has swallowed some car keys.
    </text>
  </fact>
</facts>